# **Chris Esquerra**

210-763-6803 esquerrac@gmail.com <a></a> https://esquerrac.github.io

A software developer with over 10 years of military service focused on delivering, marketing, and managing healthcare. I bring a background centered on multidisciplinary teamwork and collaboration to the tech industry. I aim to grow myself and those around me with my desire to solve problems and develop the highest quality product possible on any given project.

#### **Skills**

- HTML5
- CSS3, Bootstrap
- Javascript, JQuery
- Instruction
- Team Leadership
- Employee Development
  Conflict Resolution
- **Customer Interaction**
- Public Speaking

# **Experience**

MARCH 2013 - MAY 2016

## Family Advocacy Assistant Director / USAF, San Antonio, Texas

Managed family maltreatment intervention and prevention services to over 60k beneficiaries. Supervised and ensured educational currency of 35 staff members at 3 geographic locations in accordance with federal regulations and healthcare accreditation standards.

FEBRUARY 2012 - MARCH 2013

# Mental Health Marketing&Education/ USAF, Republic of Korea

Created and distributed mental health, substance abuse, and family maltreatment prevention content to over 20 squadrons of active duty and civilian personnel by conducting group classes, formal theater presentations, and radio broadcasts at several locations in country.

JUNE 2010 - FEBRUARY 2012

## Substance Abuse Counselor/ USAF, Omaha, Nebraska

Provided direct counseling services to active duty personnel diagnosed with substance abuse disorders and those with substance related incidents. Coordinated care with community facilities to ensure continuity of care and provide improved treatment outcomes for patients.

#### **Education**

JULY 2018 - PRESENT

### Full Stack Web Development-Java/ Codeup, San Antonio, Texas

Immersive, project driven 18 week career accelerator program with over 600 hours of expert instruction and keyboard time in software development.

OCTOBER 2016 - JUNE 2018

# BS Criminal Justice/ Strayer University, San Antonio, Texas

Currently awaiting major reassignment to Computer Science following completion of Codeup program. Expected graduation date 2020.